ama.ab.ca 2016-11-21

# Privacy Policy

SAVE $42 when you buy a Plus membership. Use promo code SAVINGS. Excludes Gift memberships. [Read More](https://ama.ab.ca/membership-rewards/compare-memberships/) close

_Click here for the Alberta Motor Association Website Usage and Privacy Statement._

## Introduction

The Alberta Motor Association is a membership organization where the action of every individual promotes quality service, safety and protection for our members’ peace of mind.

In accordance with AMA’s Visions, Values and Expected Behaviours, AMA is committed to safeguarding your privacy by protecting personal information you provide to us. AMA’s Privacy Policy complies with all governing privacy legislation. Our Privacy Policy applies to the Alberta Motor Association and its affiliates:

Alberta Motor Association Insurance Company;  
AMA Agencies Ltd.;  
AMA Properties Ltd.;  
AMA Foundation For Traffic Safety;  
and  
Bridgewater Bank (who may have additional privacy policies and statements).

AMA and its affiliates are referred to as AMA throughout this Privacy Policy.

## Personal information

Personal information is information about an identifiable individual. Personal information can include your name, address, telephone number (home and business), e-mail address, date of birth, place of employment, and the nature, frequency and type of AMA services used by you. The amount and nature of the personal information AMA may require will depend on the type of products or services you request. For certain information intensive offerings, such as insurance or financial services, additional appropriate personal information may be collected to provide you with the particular service or product you have requested. The choice to provide AMA with your personal information is always yours, but may affect the availability and quality of the products and services available.

## Why AMA collects personal information

AMA is committed to providing an extensive and superior range of products and services to our members. AMA collects your personal information so that we may maintain your membership, provide you with the products and services you have requested and provide you with the other benefits of membership. Your personal information is used to understand your needs and preferences, determine whether AMA products and services meet your needs, and develop or improve products and services. AMA presently offers and informs you about AMA products and services, or those of AMA partners that we believe may be of interest to you.

## How your personal information is used

AMA uses your personal information to maintain your membership, to communicate with you, to deliver the services and products you have requested, to provide you with responsible and reliable value-added advice, to offer additional products and services AMA believes may be of benefit and interest to you and to advise you of other benefits of AMA membership.

## Your personal information is used for proper purposes only

AMA will safeguard your personal information and use it only for the purposes that it was collected for as permitted by you or under applicable laws. AMA will not sell, rent or give away your personal information. AMA does contract with certain service providers approved by AMA, who may occasionally have access to your personal information. However, these providers are allowed access to member information only when necessary, and are bound by strict contractual obligations designed to protect the privacy and security of your personal information.

## Employees

AMA employees are informed and educated on the importance of protecting the privacy of our members, and are expected to maintain the confidentiality of AMA member information at all times.

## AMA’s commitment

AMA will protect your privacy, and in particular your personal information, in accordance with the 10 Principles of Privacy. These principles have been established by the Government of Canada and the Government of Alberta.

  1. **Accountability**  
AMA is responsible for personal information under its control. AMA will designate one or more persons who are accountable for compliance with the 10 Principles of Privacy.
  2. **Identifying Purposes  
**AMA will identify the purposes for which personal information is collected at or before the time the information is collected.
  3. **Consent  
**Consent is required for AMA’s collection, use or disclosure of personal information, except where required or permitted by law. Consent can be implied, deemed or expressly given.
  4. **Limiting Collection**  
Personal information collected will be limited to that which is necessary for the purposes identified by AMA.
  5. **Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention**  
AMA will not use or disclose personal information for purposes other than those for which the information was collected, except with your consent or as required by law. AMA will retain personal information only for as long as is necessary to fulfill the purposes for collecting such information.
  6. **Accuracy  
**Personal information will be maintained by AMA in an accurate, complete and up-to-date form as is necessary to fulfill the purposes for which the personal information is to be used.
  7. **Safeguards**  
AMA will protect personal information with security safeguards appropriate to the sensitivity of the information.
  8. **Openness  
**AMA will make readily available its policies and practices relating to the management of personal information.
  9. **Customer Access**  
Upon request AMA will inform you of the existence, use and disclosure of your personal information. We can also provide you access to your personal information, subject to any legal restrictions. You may verify the accuracy and completeness of your personal information, and may request that the information be corrected or updated, if appropriate.
  10. **Challenging Compliance  
**You may direct any questions or inquiries concerning our compliance with AMA’s Privacy Policy to the Chief Privacy Officer. The contact information is listed at the bottom of this page.

## Fees

AMA may charge, in accordance with applicable laws, a reasonable fee for access to personal information and for making copies of personal information requested.

## Information collected to date

AMA is operating on the understanding that we have your consent to use and disclose your personal information collected to date, and to do so in accordance to our Privacy Policy. However, you may refuse or withdraw your consent at any time, subject to legal or contractual restrictions and providing AMA with reasonable notice of the withdrawal of your consent. If you choose to withdraw consent or not provide certain personal information, your decision may limit the services and products AMA can offer and may make it more difficult for AMA to provide you with advice.

## AMA Website Privacy

AMA provides a number of benefits and services through our website ([ama.ab.ca](http://www.ama.ab.ca/)), many of which are exclusive to AMA members. When you visit AMA’s website without registering or logging in, your personal information and e-mail address are not recorded. AMA does track depersonalized usage of its website using tools such as Google Analytics.

To gain access to AMA member on-line exclusive services, you will have to identify yourself as an AMA member and provide some personal information in the sign up process. In addition, the AMA website uses “cookies” solely to identify you as a return visitor.

Our e-mail interaction with our members and customers are compliant with Canadian Anti-Spam Legislation. AMA does not send unsolicited e-mail and does not sell personal information, like your e-mail address, to third-parties.

When you leave AMA’s website by linking to another website, you are subject to the privacy and security policies of the new website. AMA encourages you to read the privacy policies of all websites you visit, especially if you shared any personal information with them. For further information on AMA Internet privacy, visit [AMA’s Website Usage and Privacy Statement](http://ama.ab.ca/general/internet-privacy "AMA’s Website Usage Statement").

## Questions and access

If you need to update or correct your address, phone number or membership payment information, please contact the AMA Membership Department at 1-800-222-6400.

If you have any questions or concerns about AMA’s Privacy Policy, practices or your personal information we may have on file please contact:

Chief Privacy Officer  
Alberta Motor Association  
P.O. Box 8180 Station South  
Edmonton, Alberta T6H 5X9  
Phone: (780) 430-5754  
Fax: (780) 430-5751  
Email: [privacy.officer@ama.ab.ca](mailto:privacy.officer@ama.ab.ca)

## Intellectual Property

**Trademarks**

CAA, CAA PLUS, Approved Auto Repair Services design and ERS are owned by and use is granted by the Canadian Automobile Association.

TourBook, CampBook, TripTik and Show Your Card & Save are owned by and use is granted by the American Automobile Association.

The CAA name and logo displayed throughout CAA websites and all related products and service names are the trade-marks, service marks or registered trade-marks of the Canadian Automobile Association (“CAA”). Reproduction of any of these marks without the express written consent of CAA is strictly prohibited.

**Design & Image Notice**  
The design of this site remains the intellectual property of AMA. Reproduction of the design or any images used herein is strictly prohibited.
